Register of the Chang Kia-ngau papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Chang Kia-ngau papers
1856-1981
74058
Hoover Institution Archives
26 manuscript boxes, 5 oversize boxes, 1 card file box, 1 envelope, 4 panels of calligraphy (31.4 linear feet)
Diaries, letters, writings, reports, financial records, instructions, statistics, and printed matter relating to financial and economic conditions in China, economic conditions in Manchuria at the end of World War II, Chinese-Soviet negotiations for the return of Manchuria to Chinese control, and daily commodity prices of Chinese products, 1950-1957. Includes some materials collected from Japanese organizations, calligraphy by Liang Qichao, and letters by Chiang Kai-shek. Part of collection also available on microfilm (11 reels).
Chang, Kia-ngau, 1889-1979.
Liang, Qichao, 1873-1929.
Chiang, Kai-shek, 1887-1975.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Related Materials
Last Chance in Manchuria: The Diary of Chang Kia-ngau, edited by Donald G. Gillin and Ramon H. Myers, translated by Dolores Zen. Hoover Institution Press, 1989.
Biographical Note
1888 Born, outside of Shanghai, China
1910 Editor-in-chief of the Official Gazette published by the Ministry of Communications
1913 Began his banking career as assistant manager of the Bank of China in Shanghai
1913-1935 Contributed to the development of modern practices in private banking in China, fending off government control of the Bank of China
1935 Minister of Railways
1935-1943 During the Sino-Japanese war, served as Minister of Communications, accompanying the central government from Nanking to Chungking
1935-1943 Minister of Transportation
1947-1948 President, Central Bank, China Held various other positions of importance in the Chinese Nationalist Government
1979 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
Diaries, letters, writings, reports, financial records, instructions, statistics, and printed matter relating to financial and economic conditions in China, economic conditions in Manchuria at the end of World War II, Chinese-Soviet negotiations for the return of Manchuria to Chinese control, and daily commodity prices of Chinese products, 1950-1957. Includes some materials collected from Japanese organizations, calligraphy by Liang Qichao, and letters by Chiang Kai-shek. Part of collection also available on microfilm (11 reels).
Prices--China.; Reconstruction (1939-1951)--China--Manchuria.; China--Economic conditions.; China--Foreign relations--Soviet Union.; Manchuria (China)--Economic conditions.; Manchuria (China)--History--1945-; Soviet Union--Foreign relations--China.; Finance, Public--China.
- Diaries, 1856-1981
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes diaries documenting the Japanese invasion of Manchuria.
  - Ping Shou Chai diary, 1856-1864 (Box-folder 28: 1-5)
  - 1935 June-November (Box-folder 15: 20)
  - 1937 February-June (Box-folder 15: 21)
  - 1937 June-September (Box-folder 15: 22)
  - 1937 September-December (Box-folder 15: 23)
  - 1938 May-October (Box-folder 15: 24)
  - 1938 October - 1939 May (Box-folder 15: 25)
  - Dong Bei Jie Shou Jiao She Ri Ji (Diary of Taking Over Northeastern China), 1945-1946 (Box-folder 12: 1-2)
  - Diaries and small memorandums, 1963-1981 (Box 16)
    One diary is from 1940; unclear if actually used in that year. There is also a photo inside it of an unidentified woman.
- Biographical File, 1934-1979, undated
  - Chiang Shih-hsun estate records, 1934 (Box-folder 27: 14)
  - Photographs of China Merchandise Committee, 1936 (Box-folder 27: 3)
  - Personnel records, 1945 (Box-folder 27: 18)
  - Newspaper clippings about Chang Kia-Ngau, 1945-1969 (Box-folder 27: 15)
  - Chen Kuang-Pu biographical materials, 1955 (Box-folder 21: 15)
  - Last will and testament, 1979 (Box-folder 21: 2)
  - Autobiography, undated (Box-folder 21: 3)
  - Business cards, undated (Box 17)
  - Fortune telling materials, undated (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Name and address clippings, undated (Box-folder 15: 19)
    Includes notes.
- Correspondence, 1942-1976, undated
  - Letter of appointment by Chiang Kai-shek, 1942, 1945 (Box-folder 27: 19)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1949-1976 (Box-folder 27: 9)
    Contains envelope for Chang Chinn-mau letter regarding conditions after World War II, and the decisions of Chiang Kai-shek, but letter itself is not included.
  - Telegrams, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 23: 7)
  - Chen Kuang-Pu correspondence, 1957, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 21: 6)
  - Chen Kuang-Pu correspondence, 1964 (Box-folder 21: 16)
  - Travel records and correspondence, circa 1962-1963 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - Chiang Ching-kuo, Kung Ling-kan, Li Kuo-ting, and Yen Chia-kan correspondence, undated (Box-folder 27: 2)
  - Chiang Kai-shek correspondence, undated (Box-folder 27: 13)
    Photocopy
  - Chou, Tsao-min introduction materials, undated (Box-folder 27: 7)
  - Correspondence and memoranda of meetings with Tian-Yi Xiong, undated (Box-folder 23: 8)
  - Personal instructions from Chiang Kai-shek (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - Sen Bai correspondence regarding Communist party affairs, undated (Box-folder 27: 12)
- Speeches and Writings, 1964-1968, undated
  See also: Reports and Financial Records and Shanghai Commercial Bank Documents.
  - "Studies on the Economic History of Modern China," publishing materials, 1964 (Box-folder 27: 8)
  - "Devaluation of U.S. Dollar and Britain's Currency" speech, 1968 (Box-folder 27: 5)
  - Chen Kuang-Pu biography drafts, undated (Box-folder 23: 1-2)
  - Chen Kuang-Pu biography, edited draft, undated (Box-folder 24: 5-7)
  - Chen Kuang-Pu Xian Sheng Zhuan Ji Gao (drafts for Chen Kuang-Pu's biography), undated (Box-folder 21: 14)
  - Draft chapters 9-11 of a book about bank management, undated (Box-folder 21: 9)
  - Epitaph of Zhang Jun Run, undated (Box-folder 27: 21)
  - Hai Guang Wen Xuan (Selected Works of Hai Guang), undated (Box-folder 22: 2)
  - Incomplete draft on rehabilitation after the Anti-Japanese war, undated (Box-folder 21: 8)
  - Miscellaneous study notes, undated (Box-folder 27: 17)
  - Notebook of economic research, undated (Box-folder 24: 8)
  - Zhong Guo Yin Hang Yu Huo Bi Chao Xiang Xian Dai Hua (The Modernization of Chinese Currency and Banking), undated (Box-folder 21: 12)
- Reports and Financial Records, 1876-1962, undated
  See also: Banking Reports.
  - Railroads-China records, 1876-1937 (Box-folder 27: 11)
  - Soy Beans in Manchuria, 1926 (Box-folder 27: 22)
  - Reports of Coal Mining Resources, 1937-1941 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Wu Nian Kai Fa Ji Hua (Five Year Development Plan), 1937-1941 (Box-folder 10: 9, 11: 2)
  - Business materials of Man Zhou Guo, 1937-1945 (Box-folder 7: 2-3)
  - Chan Ye Huo Dong Ji Qi Zu Ai (The Progress and the Obstacles of the Industries) reports, 1940 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - You Ri Man Tie Gong Ye Zi Ben Gou Cheng Suo Jian Zhi Man Zhou Kuang Gong Ye Zhi Dong Xiang (Analysis Report About the Future of Coal Mining Industry in Manchuria Based on the Capital Structure of the Manchurian Railway), 1940-1942 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - Ge Gang Xian Zhuang Ping Mian Tu (Plans of All Harbors), 1940-1945 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - Industrial production reports, 1940-1945 (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - 1941 Sheng Chan Huo Dong Gai Kuang (Overview of Articles on Industrial Production in 1941) (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - Iron and steel purchasing reports, 1941 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Gang Wan He Yi Ji Xie Yi Lan Biao (Blueprints of Industrial Machinery from the Netherlands), 1942 (Box-folder 9: 1-2)
  - Industrial Chemicals Supply report, 1942 (Box-folder 6: 3-6)
  - Lao Dong Zi Liao (Labor Distribution in Different Industries), 1942 (Box-folder 5: 6-7)
  - The Status Quo and Future Plans of Heavy Industries in Man Zhou Guo, 1942 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - Papers about iron and steel, 1942-1945 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Assets Lists of Soviet Preoccupied Infrastructure, 1943 (Box-folder 14: 13)
    Oversize documents
  - Gang Tie Yue Bao (Report of Iron and Steel), 1943 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Hua Xue Gong Ye Yao Pin Zhi Xu Gong Ce Ding Biao (Chemical Supply and Demand List), 1943 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - Nong Chan Wu Gou Ru Jia Ge Shuo An Yao Ling (Price Index of Crops), 1943 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Nong Ye Jin Rong Diao Cha Bao Gao (Agricultural Finance Survey Report), 1943 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Nong Ye Zi Liao (Agricultural Materials), 1943 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Foreign trade reports, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - Mineral distribution plans, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Man Ye Man Tie Ge Xiang Can She Zi Liao (Materials About South Manchurian Industries and Railway), 1944 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Wu Dong Yuan Liao Biao (Raw Material Lists for Steel and Aircraft Manufacturing), 1944 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Zhong Guo Zhi Bi Lun and Dong Bei Jin Rong Zheng Ce (Financial and Currency Policy of Northeast China Drafted by Japanese Government), 1944 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Nong Chan Wu Sheng Chan Diao Cha (A Survey About Crop Yield), 1944-1945 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Contracts of Major Agreement on Railway in East-Central China, 1945 (Box-folder 26: 8)
  - Gong Ye Zi Liao (Industrial Materials), 1945 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Man Tie You Guan Wen Jian (Materials About the South Manchurian Railway), 1945 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - Man Zhou Zong He Dang Pu Gai Lan (Materials About Pawnshops in Manchuria), 1945 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Manchuria corporations files, 1945 (Box-folder 14: 12)
  - Hua Xue Gong Ye Diao Cha Bao Gao (Survey Reports About Chemical Industries), 1945-1946 (Box-folder 8: 5-6)
  - Industrial and agricultural maps, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - Railway maps, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 10: 8)
  - Zhong Yang Jun Zhan Lin Di Qu Nei Nong Chan Wu Jia Ge Tiao Jie (The Adjustment of Primary Goods Price Within the Central Military Occupation), 1945-1946 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Fu Gong Ji Hua (Budget for Rebooting Steel Manufacturing), 1945-1947 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Dong Bei Cai Zheng (Fiscal Materials of Northeastern China), 1946 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - Dong Bei Ri Ren Lai Hu Gong Zuo Bao Gao (The Working Reports of Japanese in North-Eastern China), 1946 (Box-folder 11: 7-8)
  - Fei Tie Jin Shu Bao Gao (Reports of Non-iron Metal Resources), 1946 (Box-folder 7: 4-5, 8: 1)
  - Finance Reports of Southern Manchuria, 1946 (Box-folder 26: 4)
  - Liu Tong Bu Men Wu Jia (Price Policy of Northeast China drafted by Japanese Government), 1946 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Mei Kuang Fu Xing Dui Ce (Rehabilitation of Coal Mining Industry) policy files, 1946 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Negotiation materials for taking over Manchuria from Russia, 1946 (Box-folder 26: 3)
  - Qing Gong Ye Jian She Yi Jian (Proposals for Light Industry Development in China), 1946 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - The Rehabilitation of the Textile Industry of the Nine Northeastern Provinces, 1946 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Report on Japanese Assets in Manchuria to the President of the United States, 1946 (Box-folder 27: 10)
  - Reports of Mineral Resources in China, 1946 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Science and Technology Conception for Northeast China, 1946 (Box-folder 1: 7)
    Drafted by the Japanese Science Committee.
  - Science and Technology Education, Healthcare Policies for North East China, 1946 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Sheng Chan Guan Li Ju Di Yi Qi Fu Gong Ji Hua (First Phase of Manufacturing Rebooting), 1946 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Tie Lu Fu Yuan Ji Hua (The Plan for Railway Rehabilitation), 1946 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Zhi Jiang Ji Zhi Zhi Gong Ye (Paper Industry) reports, 1946 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Zhong Chang Lu Cha Juan (Railway Construction files); miscellaneous Russian property materials, memos, and correspondence on Northeast China, 1946 (Box-folder 26: 5)
  - Zhong Guo Chan Ye Kai Fa, Dong Bei Gong Ye Fu Xing (Proposals for Heavy Industry Development in China), 1946 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Hui Fu Jing Ji Shi Ye Jin Zhan (Rehabilitation of Economics) articles, 1947 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Jie Shou Ge Shi Ye Dan Wei Fen Lei Biao (List of Institutions Taken Over), 1947 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - Ri Ren Yi Jian Shu (Reconstruction Proposals from Japanese Scientists), 1947 (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - Sino-Soviet Treaty of Friendship, Alliances, and Mutual Assistance, 1949 (Box-folder 26: 7)
  - Materials about taking over coal mining industry in Northeastern China, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 26: 2)
  - Price statistics of cotton, etamine, and other materials, 1950-1956 (Box 30)
    Includes 16 lists.
  - Price statistics of food in Shanghai and Beijing, 1950-1956 (Box 30)
    Includes 42 lists.
  - Statistics of coal, steel, construction materials, and wood in Beijing, Tianjing and Chongqing, 1950-1956 (Box 29)
    Includes 25 lists.
  - Agricultural products price lists, 1950-1957 (Box-folder 14: 11)
  - Unit price lists of Chinese textiles, 1950-1957 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - Paofoong Insurance Company materials, 1950-1963 (Box-folder 21: 17)
  - Price list of Chinese medicine, 1951-1954 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - Price statistics of Chinese traditional medicine, 1951-1954 (Box 29)
    Includes 6 lists.
  - Price statistics of construction materials, bricks, wood and cement in Shanghai, 1951-1954 (Box 29)
    Includes 12 lists.
  - Price statistics of paper, 1951-1954 (Box 29)
    Includes 5 lists.
  - Unit price lists of chemicals, medicines, and papers, 1951-1955 (Box-folder 15: 17)
  - Price statistics of general merchandise in Shanghai, 1951-1956 (Box 30)
    Includes 21 lists.
  - Price statistics of medicine, chemicals and dye in Shanghai, Tianjing, Wuhan, and Qingdao, 1951-1956 (Box 29)
    Includes 24 lists.
  - Coal price and gas price, 1951-1957 (Box-folder 14: 10)
  - Machinery materials price lists, 1951-1957 (Box-folder 14: 9)
  - Unit price lists of chemicals and medicines, 1951-1957 (Box-folder 14: 6)
  - Unit price lists of steel and building materials, 1951-1957 (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - Yearly price lists of general merchandise in Shanghai, Qingdao, and Guangzhou, 1951-1957 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  - General Commodity Quotations in Hong Kong Market, 1951-1963 (Box-folder 15: 16)
  - Yearly paper quotations, 1952-1955 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - Price statistics of cotton, cement, sugar, acid, fertilizer, rice, paper, soda, steel, paper, iron, tobacco and other materials, 1952-1957 (Box 30)
  - Materials about Hong Kong banking and business reports of Shanghai Commercial Bank, Hong Kong, 1952-1964 (Box-folder 24: 1-3)
  - Food supply materials, 1956-1961 (Box-folder 27: 20)
  - Zhong Guo Lu She Jian Shi (The History of China Travel Agency), 1962 (Box-folder 21: 13)
    Drafts and printed copy
  - Correspondence, notes, and memos on returning companies to Chinese control from the Soviet Union. Cooperation between Chinese and Soviet industry (Box-folder 12: 4-5)
  - Gang Wan Shi She (Engineering Drawings of Manchuria Harbor Construction), undated (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - An investigation of Chinese government officials' overseas bank accounts, undated (Box-folder 27: 4)
  - Monthly quotations of general merchandise (Box-folder 14: 2)
  - Shanghai household utility price (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - Soviet and Chinese memos, agreements on Japanese reparations and property (Box-folder 26: 6)
- Banking Reports, 1919-1957
  - Currency samples, 1919-1929 (Box-folder 15: 18)
  - Joint Statement made by the Secretary of the Treasury and the Minister of Finance of China for press release, 1937 July 9 (Box-folder 21: 10)
  - China Finance Analysis Reports, 1941-1949 (Box-folder 27: 6)
  - National income survey, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Fiscal material of Manchuria, 1944 (Box-folder 3: 3-4)
  - Financial materials of Manchurian currency and price index, 1945 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Fiscal and taxation materials, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Dong Bei Wu Jia (Price Index materials), 1945-1946 (Box-folder 10: 5-6)
  - Finance materials, 1946 (Box-folder 10: 3-4)
  - Memorandum of meetings with Malinovsky and general principles on economic enterprises, 1946 (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - Statement of cash flow, 1948 (Box-folder 23: 6)
  - Daily Commodity Quotations, 1952 (Box-folder 12: 6-9)
  - Daily Commodity Quotations, 1953 (Box-folder 12: 10-16)
  - Daily Commodity Quotations, 1954 (Box-folder 13: 1-13)
  - Daily Commodity Quotations, 1955 (Box-folder 13: 14-25)
    November is not included.
  - Index of files about Chinese banking and finance from Xu Xiekang, 1955 June (Box-folder 21: 5)
  - Daily Commodity Quotations, 1956 (Box-folder 13: 26-31)
  - Daily Commodity Quotations, 1956 (Box-folder 15: 1-5)
  - Daily Commodity Quotations, 1957 (Box-folder 15: 6-15)
- Shanghai Commercial Bank Documents, 1915-1967, undated
  - Official reports compilations of Shanghai Commercial Bank, 1915-1935 (Box 31)
  - Financial reports of Shanghai Commercial Bank, 1932-1943 (Box-folder 22: 5-7)
  - Financial reports of Shanghai Commercial Bank, 1935-1949 (Box 32)
    Items in this box were formerly in Box 29.
  - Work diaries about transformation of Shanghai Commercial Bank after Anti-Japanese War, 1939-1979
    - 1939, 1941-1943, 1945, 1946, 1948 (Box 18)
    - 1961, 1963, 1968-1973 (Box 19)
    - 1974-1979 (Box 20)
  - A stock certificate of Shanghai Commercial Bank, 1947 (Box-folder 27: 16)
  - Shanghai Commercial Bank balance sheets, 1951-1958, 1963 (Box-folder 23: 3)
  - "History of Shanghai Commercial Bank" documents, 1951-1965
    - Drafts of "History of Shanghai Commercial Bank,", 1951 (Box-folder 22: 3)
    - References for "Fiftieth Anniversary of Shanghai Commercial Bank,", 1958-1960 (Box-folder 25: 7-8)
    - Chapters 1-5 of "Fiftieth Anniversary of Shanghai Commercial Bank,", 1965 (Box-folder 25: 2)
    - "Fiftieth Anniversary of Shanghai Commercial Bank,", 1965 (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - First draft of "Fiftieth Anniversary of Shanghai Commercial Bank,", 1965 (Box-folder 25: 5)
    - Draft of "History of Shanghai Commercial Bank,", undated (Box-folder 23: 5)
    - Drafts of "History of Shanghai Commercial Bank,", undated (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - Drafts of "History of Shanghai Commercial Bank,", undated (Box-folder 25: 3-4)
    - Materials for "Fiftieth Anniversary of Shanghai Commercial Bank,", undated (Box-folder 25: 6)
    - "Shanghai Bank in 1951,", undated (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - Correspondence (in English) with Lawrence Morris, E. K. Hsu, George H. Greene, Ambassador Hollington K. Tong, Bang How; summary of Shanghai Commercial Bank and US Treasury and frozen funds, miscellaneous Chinese note, 1956-1957, 1963 (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Paperwork from Shanghai Commercial Bank, 1957 (Box-folder 21: 11)
  - Minutes of a board meeting of Shanghai Commercial Bank, 1960 (Box-folder 21: 7)
  - Annual Report to the share holders of Shanghai Commercial Bank, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - Board Meeting reports of Shanghai Commercial Bank in Taiwan, 1964-1967 (Box-folder 22: 4)
  - Notebook of Chinese Fiscal and Currency Policies, undated (Box-folder 23: 4)
- Photographs, undated
  - 1 print depicting Chang Kia-ngau (Envelope A)
- Memorabilia, undated (Memorabilia cabinet)
  - Four panels of calligraphy
  - Two late Ch'ing Dynasty teacups